# Pooja Mishra

Pune, India | LinkedIn | +91 7755906554 | PoojMishra91@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Seasoned Business Analyst/ Product Owner (PSPO I certified) with 10 years of experience, in building and supporting IT solutions across Europe and Asian markets. Proficient in Project Management activities, understanding and supporting business processes, requirement feasibility analysis, issue resolution, stakeholder management and documentation.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM Consulting Pvt Ltd Pune, India

Business Analyst

April 2021 - Present

- Conducted thorough analysis of client's products, services, stakeholders, and technologies for IBM Net Zero & EV strategy/Campaign.
- Generated actionable insights by analysing trends and patterns of the customer behaviour which helped IBM create a targeted customer acquisition strategy.
- Responsible for the implementation of the quarterly change in the DTC and UK Link.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including Business Stakeholders and Development team, to design and implement solutions compliant with Of gem regulations, resulting in an increase in customer satisfaction by 20%.
- Created Analysis Report and Design Specification (ARDS) Documents defining the As-Is and To-Be processes.
- Monitored and reviewed requirement traceability catalogs and Solution design documents to ensure they meet the project gate criteria.
- Responsible for the Impact Assessment report for the Google migration project.
- Successfully delivered projects with NPS Score 9+.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to identify key pain points in the existing process and facilitated implementation of new processes resulting in a 20% increase in efficiency.

Birlasoft India Ltd Pune, India

Lead Consultant

November 2019 - April 2021

- Spearheaded a team of 5 consultants in resolving 450+ incidents, resulting in a 98% customer satisfaction rate and a decrease in incident resolution time by 10%.
- Responsible for changes in the existing Business Process and provide ongoing application support for the SAP CRM and ERP modules.
- Implemented effective incident management, change management, and problem management processes covering areas such as training management, contract management, activity management, and account management to ensure timely issue resolution with minimal downtime for end-users.

### Fujitsu Consulting india Pvt Ltd

Pune, India

CRM Domain Expert

*May 2019 – November 2019* 

- Led Incident resolution team of 5 consultants. Resolved 300+ incidents/issues.
- Streamlined the existing Business Process, reducing inefficiencies by 15%, and provided ongoing application support for SAP CRM and ERP modules, resulting in increased productivity for end-users.
- Responsible for change management, incident management and Problem management. Worked on Incidents covering areas Replication, Contract management, Activity management and Account management.

# **Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd**

Pune, India

Application Development Senior Analyst

August 2013 - May 2019

- **Revamped the New Connection process** by leveraging on a digital platform to provide a seamless customer experience, with reduced customer interaction and lead time for new supply connection. Supply delivery time decreased from **4 months to 1 months**.
- Implemented Customer Care system to notify 320k Smart meter customers for Planned/unplanned Outages, restoration, reconnection, disconnection and tariff changes via various Channels like SMS, Email, Mobile App and Web portal.

- Developed and executed an improved process flow, eliminating the need for SSP connection to ERMS and BCRM. This resulted in a 40% reduction in application processing time and decreased errors by 25%.
- Collaborated with the **Digital team for the implementation of Flexi tariff tool** that will enable the user to launch, withdraw and renew fixed duration/ fixed end date **Products** in CRM from Digital platforms. This reduced **the Product Launch activity from 1.5-month to 3 days work**.
- Coordinated with end-users to evaluate business processes and Conducted User training for the new process understanding for 30 rangers/users.
- Have led an Incident resolution team of 7 consultants. Resolved 3000+ incidents.
- Triaged the incidents and created User Education Documents to reduce the recurring issues to 25%.
- Prepared Business Process Design (BPD) and 8 Functional Specification documents.
- Conducted, evaluated, and documented test cases.
- Debugged and resolved 30 Defects and issues.
- Worked on-site with the clients to provide high quality advice and solutions clear any queries related to the business and functional specifications

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Professional Scrum Product Owner I**: Issued By Scrum.org **Databases and SQL for Data Science**: Issued by Coursera/IBM

Energy, Environment and Utilities Industry: Issued by IBM

IBM Agile Explorer: Issued by IBM

### **EDUCATION**

Jaypee Institute of Engineering & Technology

Bachelors of Technology

Guna, India

Graduation Date: May 2013

Indian Institute of ManagementCalcutta, IndiaMDP: Executive Program for Young ManagersGraduation Date: May 2017

## SKILLS & INTERESTS

Skills: Microsoft Office (Excel, PowerPoint, Visio) | CRM (Salesforce, SAP, Mainframe) | G-Suite | Project Management Tools (Mural, Jira, Trello)| Analytics (SQL, Power BI, Tableau)| SAP ERP/ISU| Agile Scrum Methodology | Waterfall Methodology | Business Process Design | Wireframing| Requirement Gathering| Stakeholder Management|

Interests: Strategy & Operations, Analytics, CRM, Product Management